Guide to the PACE Photographs, 1964-2005 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
PACE photographs 1964-2005 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Pace (Los Angeles, Calif.)
24 linear feet Extent: Approximately 5060 Items
Magazine published in Los Angeles, California during the sixties. Collection comprises 35mm black-and-white negatives and accompanying contact sheets representing documentary images created by the photojournalists on staff at Los Angeles-based PACE magazine (formerly known as DARE), dating from the 1960s. There are some gaps in prints and negatives, but for the most part the collection represents the entire photographic morgue of PACE. Subjects include athletic and equestrian events; political events such as speeches and rallies; the Vietnam War, with images shot in Vietnam; and the organization Up With People (UWP). The photographic materials are accompanied by a full index of the volume numbers and the image numbers from each volume. Acquired as part of the Archive for Documentary Arts at Duke University.
RL.00986
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Portions of the collection are restricted: the negatives are closed to research use. Contact sheets with positive prints of negatives are open to use.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The PACE Photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2006.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises 35mm black-and-white negatives and accompanying contact sheets representing documentary images created by the photojournalists on staff at Los Angeles-based PACE magazine (formerly known as DARE), dating from the 1960s. There are some gaps in prints and negatives, but for the most part the collection represents the entire photographic morgue of PACE. Subjects include athletic and equestrian events; political events such as speeches and rallies; the Vietnam War, with images shot in Vietnam; and the organization Up With People (UWP). The photographic materials are accompanied by a full index of the volume numbers and the image numbers from each volume. Each number is also indexed individually in a spreadsheet, available in print form, with a brief description of the image. There are no contact sheets from the first volume, A. There is a small amount of correspondence between photographers and staff and a release form dating from 2005, when the collection was donated to the library. Acquired as part of the Archive for Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Collection Arrangement
The contact sheets are arranged in original order as represented in the index spreadsheet, and each folder is marked with the numerical range of the contact prints. Each volume is preceded by a set of index sheets that were found in the notebooks that once housed the contact sheets.
Subject Headings
PACE (Los Angeles, Calif.); Up With People (Organization); Photojournalism -- California; Photojournalism -- United States; Photographs -- Periodicals; Photographs -- Political aspects; Protest movements -- United States; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Contact sheets; Negatives
Contents of Collection
- Contact Sheets Series, 1964-2005 and undated, (15 boxes)
  Series consists of black and white contact sheets representing the work of photojournalists at PACE magazine. Arrnagement is in numerical order by volume number of publication. The order is the same as in the index spreadsheet, which is available in paper form in Box 1. The index briefly describes the image or the topic.
  - Full index (print-out), 2005 (Box 1)
  - Unidentified contact prints, 1960s (Box 1)
  - Volume 1 index (Box 1)
  - Volume 1 sheets, 2550-2728 (Box 1)
  - Volume 1 sheets, 18734-18787 (Box 1)
  - Volume 1 sheets, 2729-3020 (Box 2)
  - Volume 1 sheets, 18790-18818 (Box 2)
  - Volume 1 sheets, 3021-3279 (Box 3)
  - Volume 1 sheets, 18822-18858 (Box 3)
  - Volume 1 sheets, 3280-3297 (Box 4)
  - Volume 2 index (Box 4)
  - Volume 2 sheets, 3298-3320A (Box 4)
  - Volume 2 sheets, 3325-3352N (Box 5)
  - Volume 2 sheets, 3352P-3399C (Box 6)
  - Volume 2 sheet 18880 (Box 6)
  - Volume 2 sheets, 3399E-3421 (Box 7)
  - Volume 3 index (Box 7)
  - Volume 3 sheets, 3422-3429V (Box 7)
  - Volume 3 sheets, 3429W-3461ZZ (Box 8)
  - Volume 3 sheets, 18967-18984 (Box 8)
  - Volume 3 sheets, 3461AAA-3499 (Box 9)
  - Volume 3 sheets, 18947-19019 (Box 9)
  - Volume 3 sheets, 3500-3533N (Box 10)
  - Volume 3 sheets, 19012-19036 (Box 10)
  - Volume 3 sheets, 3536-3579 (Box 11)
  - Volume 4 index (Box 11)
  - Volume 4 sheets, 19038-19095 (Box 11)
  - Volume 4 sheets, 3581-3639A (Box 12)
  - Volume 4 sheets, 3640-3683Q (Box 13)
  - Volume 4 sheets, 19076-19130 (Box 13)
  - Volume 4 sheets, 3686-3740R (Box 14)
  - Volume 4 sheets, 19107-19124 (Box 14)
  - Volume 4 sheets, 3741-3807E (Box 15)
  - Up With People (UWP) index and sheets (Box 15)
  - Vietnam index (Box 15)
  - Vietnam sheets (Box 15)
  - Vietnam slides (Box 15)
  - Horse Poem, McGee, 1966 (Box 15)
  - PACE Correspondence (Box 15)
  - PACE Photographer Letter (Box 15)
- Negatives Series, 1964-1969 and undated, (1 box)
  This series is closed to public use. Contact sheets corresponding to these particular negatives related to the Vietnam War and Up With People are available for public use and can be found in Box 15.
  - Up With People (UWP) (Box 16)
  - Vietnam (Box 16)
  - Negative boxes, unprocessed
    - 895 - 1277 (Box N1)
    - 3401 - 3436 (Box N2)
    - 3730 - 3807 (Box N3)
    - 2826 - 3193 (Box N4)
    - 3312 - 3350 (Box N5)
    - 3437 - 3497 (Box N6)
    - 3352 - 3400 (Box N7)
    - no numbers given (Box N8)
    - 3572 - 3639 (Box N9)
    - 3498 - 3556 (Box N10)
    - 3200 - 3310 (Box N11)
    - 3652 - 3727 (Box N12)